# **Alexander Davis**

Adept at interpersonal communication, leadership and teamwork. Able to learn quickly and remain flexible under pressure. Experienced in customer service, money handling and volunteer work. Enthusiastic about coding and using technology to help solve real world problems.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Long's CVS, Hawaii Kai HI — Pharmacy Technician

Oct 2016 - Feb 2017

Promoted from a clerk to a pharmacy tech in less than a month. Filled and organized medication for customers, contacted customers regarding insurance or stock issues and with refill reminders. Retrieved customer medications, handled financial transactions and provided excellent customer service.

# Mattress Firm, Chicago IL — Traveling Sales Manager

March 2016 - Sept 2016

Responsible for maximizing sales, coordinating with the local warehouse on inventory and delivery issues and deposited any cash payments when necessary. Managed store operations such as cleaning, setting up signage and scheduling deliveries. Visited multiple stores a week to assist with sales and operations and worked with regional management to increase the overall performance of the region.

# **Advantage Rental Car,** Honolulu HI — *Customer Service Representative*

July 2013 – Jan 2016

Earned a promotion to run the Waikiki location as solo agent on duty responsible for fleet management vehicle reservations, returns and maximizing sales at the location. Maximized sales through vehicle upgrades, selling insurance policies and prepaid fuel purchases.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# Innovative Concepts Church, Honolulu, HI -- Operations Assistant

Jan 2008 - Jan 2016

Managed storage facility and kept stock/replenished essential supplies. Coordinated equipment distribution to different church events and services. Lead operations for youth service and was operations assistant for adult service which consisted of recruiting, training and managing a team of volunteers.

Phone: 808-294-9566 https://github.com/adavis001 akonidavis@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex ander-davis-8b5968138/

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL

### **WEB SKILLS**

- -Responsive/Mobile First Web Development
- -Test/Behavior Driven Development
- -Relational and Non-Relational Database Modeling
- -User Authentication
- -API Integration

#### FRONTEND PROFICIENCIES

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, React, Redux, Angular, SASS

# **SERVER-SIDE PROFICIENCIES**

NodeJS, Express

#### DATABASE PROFICIENCIES

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, D3

# WORKFLOW/TESTING UTILITIES

Git, Gulp, Mocha, Chai

# **EDUCATION**

# DevLeague, Honolulu HI

Jan 2017 - June 2017

DevLeague is a full stack web development boot camp provides over 800 hours of practical programing experience that prepares students for a real-world working environment.

**University of Hawaii at Manoa,** Honolulu HI — Bachelor of Speech Communication

Graduated May 2010

Saint Louis High School, Honolulu HI — High School Diploma

Graduated May 2005

# DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Plan-it-Better - May 2017

https://github.com/planit-better/plan-it-better

Plan-it-better is an event planning app specialized in contacting your entire guest list via text message or e-mail and keeping track of the event's budget. Final project for DevLeague, which had me as acting project manager responsible for initial wireframing, delegating tasks to my teammates and defining our minimum viable product in order to meet our two week deadline. Assisted in the creation of the database and API routing for this project and was responsible for deploying our app to the web

# React Kanban - March 2017

https://github.com/adavis001/React-Kanban

An interactive to-do list that separates tasks into three separate columns: "Queue", "In Progress" and "Done". Users are able to add a new task with varying levels of priority and assign it to a specific person and dynamically change the status of individual tasks based on its progress.